So, to use a while loop to repeat something for a specific number of times,
所以 要用 while 循环 以一定次数重复某件事
we need to have those three components: the loop counter,
我们得用到这三个重要部分 循环计数器、
our loop condition, and our loop increment.
循环条件以及循环增量
They all have to work together to make sure that our loop keeps
这三个部分需要共同合作
repeating for the specific number of times we need it to.
确保循环会以我们要的次数重复执行
However, Java actually offers another type of loops called for loops,
不过事实上 Java 提供了另一种循环 叫做 for 循环
which is basically a shorthand of what we've just done using the while loops here.
其功能基本与我们在这用 while 循环做的事一样 不过写起来更方便
Let's see how we could have implemented the raiseAlarm function using for loops.
我们来看看要怎么用 for 循环来实现 raiseAlarm 函数
For loops are written like so,
for 循环写起来是这样的
for followed by parentheses and three sections here separated by semi-colons.
for 后面是括号 然后这里有三个部分 由分号隔开
These three sections are basically those three steps that we did with a while loop.
这三个部分基本上就是我们在 while 循环里做的那三步
The first section here would have our loop counter,
第一个部分放循环计数器
which is integer i=1,
也就是 int (整数) i=1
so that matches number one here.
和这里的第一条对应
The second section is our loop condition exactly the same as we did with a while loop,
第二个部分是循环条件 和 while 循环完全相同
i &lt;= to the numOfWarnings,
即 i &lt;= numOfWarnings
so that maps number two here,
和这里的第二条对应
and the last section is our loop increment,
最后一个部分是循环增量
which is just i++,
就是 i++
which matches number three up here.
和上面的第三条对应
However, notice that we don't have a semi-colon following the i++.
不过 注意 i++ 后面没有分号
We only have those two semi-colons separating these three sections.
我们只用这两个分号来分隔这三个部分
So, our for loop that does exactly what this does is written as so: for integer i=1;
所以 虽然 for 循环要做的事和这个完全相同 但要写成这样
i &lt;= numOfWarnings; i++.
for (int i = 1; i &lt;= numOfWarnings ; i++ )
And then inside those curly brackets we write whatever instruction we want to repeat.
然后在花括号里面 我们想重复执行什么指令就写什么
Again, notice that we're not doing the increment inside the loop anymore,
注意 在循环里 我们不再进行增量操作
it's part of the definition of the loop up here.
因为这个循环的定义已经包含了这部分
Let's try to trace that and see what's happening.
我们来跟踪循环 看看怎么样
As you can see already, the function looks a lot simpler when we write it with for loops.
正如你所见 用 for 循环来写的话 函数看起来简单很多
Because everything is written in the same line up here.
因为所有东西都被写到了这一行里
So let's assume, that we're going to test it again with a value five.
为了测试 我们再次假设实参为 5
So, we pass in the value five to a number of warnings and then we step inside.
于是给 numOfWarnings 赋值为 5 然后来到这里
The first thing that the for loop does is it initializes i to be equal to one,
for 循环要做的第一件事 就是把 i 初始值设为 1
and then it does the comparison which is i less than or equal to a number of warnings,
然后进行比较 判断 i 是否小于或等于 numOfWarnings
which is five, and that is true.
现在这个值是 5 所以结果为真
So, it doesn't do the increment yet,
不过它现在还不会进行增量操作
it immediately steps into the loop,
而是立刻进入循环
running this command here,
执行这里的指令
which just prints out warning.
也就是输出警告
Reached the end of the loop, so we go back up,
到达循环尾部 然后我们回到这上面来
the first thing it does is this increment.
这时循环要做的第一件事就是增量
So, once the for loop finishes an iteration,
也就是说 for 循环每完成一次迭代
the first thing it does is do this increment,
就会先进行增量操作
making i become two.
在这里就是使 i 变为 2
Once it's done with increment,
完成了增量操作
it goes and performs this check operation,
循环就会继续进行判断
is i less than or equal to the number of warnings?
i 是否小于或等于 numOfWarnings 呢？
and yes it is.
是的
Meaning, that we step inside the loop again and we print out warning.
于是我们再次进入循环 输出警告
We reached the end of the loop,
到达循环尾部
so we go back run the increment making i equals three
回来 进行增量操作 使 i 变为 3
and then we do our comparison and three is less than or equal to five.
进行比较 3 小于或等于 5
So, we step inside and we print out warning.
于是进入循环 输出警告
Keep repeating that, i for less than five,
继续重复这件事 i 为 4 小于 5
so print out a warning and the same goes when i
输出警告 然后 i 再次得到增量
gets incremented to five and that is still true.
变成 5 判断结果仍为真
So, step inside and will print out the warning.
于是进入循环 输出警告
So, now we reach the end of the loop we,
现在 我们到达了循环尾部
go back up we increment i to become six.
回来 将 i 增量为 6
We do this check,
做判断
and this time six is no longer less than or equal to five.
这一次 6 不再小于或等于 5 了
That means that we do not step into our loop.
所以我们不会进入循环
So, as you can see even tracing the variables is exactly the same as the while loop.
正如你所见 就连变量的跟踪过程也和 while 循环的完全相同
The only difference is that it's written in
唯一不同的就是写法
a compact way that's easier to read and follow.
for 循环更紧凑 可读性更强